Have you ever felt like
you were a little bit different?
Like you had something unique
to offer the world...
...if you could just get people
to see it.
Then you know exactly how it felt...
...to be me.
Go ahead, Flint.
What is the number one problem
facing our community today?
Untied shoelaces.
Which is why I've invented
a laceless alternative foot covering.
Spray-On Shoes.
-Voilà.
-They're so nifty.
How you gonna get them off, nerd?
What a freak.
He wants to be smart, but that's lame.
I wanted to run away that day.
But you can't run away
from your own feet.
Not every sardine is meant
to swim, son.
I don't understand
fishing metaphors.
-What did I say?
-Don't worry.
Honey, I think your shoes
are wonderful.
Everyone just thinks I'm a weirdo.
So?
People probably thought
that these guys were weirdoes too.
But that never stopped them.
I was saving this
for your birthday, but here.
A professional-grade lab coat.
Just like the real guys wear.
It fits perfect.
The world needs
your originality, Flint.
You just have to grow into it.
And I know that you're gonna do
big things someday.
From that moment on...
...I was determined
to invent something great.
Remote Control Television.
And the pitch is in.
Eventually.
Hair Un-Balder.
Flying Car.
Monkey Thought Translator.
-Hungry. Hungry. Hungry.
-How wise.
No, Steve. No, no, no, no, no!
No, please! Leave it--
Ratbirds.
Hey, what's going on, little guy?
Flint Lockwood.
My dream was to help
my hometown...
...a tiny island hidden under
the "A" in "Atlantic"...
...called Swallow Falls.
We were famous for sardines...
...until the day the Baby Brent
Sardine Cannery closed for good.
Right after everyone in the world
realized that sardines...
...are super gross.
Soon, all of us were stuck eating
the sardines that no one else wanted.
Poached, fried, boiled, dried,
candied and juiced.
Life became gray and flavorless.
But when all seemed lost,
I stared at defeat...
...and found hope.
My name is Flint Lockwood.
And I was about to invent
a machine...
...that turns water...
...into food.
Steve, my best friend
and trusted colleague.
Steve.
Can I count on your help?
Can.
I knew I could.
Button, on.
Memory, activate.
Blueprints, awesome.
Begin nano-mutation.
Radiation matrix, secure.
Computer, boot.
Coolness enhancement, complete.
Engage coffee break.
Networking power grid.
Beginning conversion of water...
...into food.
Hydrating protein matrix.
Calibrating flavor panel.
Priming chow plopper.
Uploading cool machine voice.
Cheeseburger.
Everyone is going to love this.
Flint!
Sorry, Dad.
Steve, keep working.
Scanning hand.
That's a really weird dude.
Re-energizing tower unit.
Jeez. See you, Dad.
Flint.
Don't you think it's time to give up
this inventing thing, get a real job?
No, why?
Well, all your technology stuff,
it just ends in disaster.
The ratbirds, yes, they escaped
and bred at a surprising rate.
But I took care of that problem
and disposed of them.
Billy, just play dead.
Flint, you don't keep throwing your net
where there aren't any fish.
-What?
-I want you to work full-time...
-...at the tackle shop.
-The tackle shop? Dad, no.
Tackle is a good career.
Please, I'm so close with this one.
I just have to hook it up to the power
station and give it power and it'll work.
And then you could sell food
in the shop...
...and then everyone won't have to eat
sardines anymore.
It is going to be so awesome.
I'm sorry, son.
No more inventing.
Dad, I know I can do this.
And Mom did too.
It had been almost 10 years
since Mom died...
...and Dad still didn't understand me
like she did.
Come on. Let's open the shop.
Tim and Son
Sardine Bait and Tackle.
You feeling it?
Look out, Baby Brent!
Baby Brent Sardines.
Hand-packed in Swallow Falls.
As your mayor, I know it's time to put
our sardine-canning past behind us...
...and look to the future.
Sardine tourism!
That's why,
without consulting anyone...
...I spent the entire town budget
on the thing that is under this tarp...
...which I will be unveiling today...
...at noon.
Featuring a live appearance
by Baby Brent himself.
What is up, everybody?
-Hey.
-Hey, it's Baby Brent.
What you doing? Stacking cans
with me on them as a baby?
Anyways, who wants to watch me
cut the ribbon...
...at the mayor's unveiling thing?
I'll be using these bad boys
to help save the town.
All right, you guys.
Sardines, yeah.
-Swallow Falls forever!
-What a delight.
Listen, you-- Maybe you wanna go
to that unveiling?
You know, Dad, why don't you
go ahead. I'll hold down the fort here.
Really? You sure you can handle it?
Yeah, Dad,
I'm pretty sure I'll be fine.
All right, then.
I'll be back in half an hour, skipper.
Okay. Bye.
This hellhole is too small
for me, Brent.
I wanna be big.
I want people to look at me and say,
"That is one big mayor."
And that's why this has to work.
It has to work.
Otherwise, I'm just a tiny mayor
of a tiny town...
...full of tiny sardine-sucking
knuckle-scrapers.
But not me, right?
Oh, not you, Brent. No.
You've always been like a son to me.
Hey, everybody.
Under this tarp is the greatest tourist
attraction ever built by humans.
We just need 17,000 more gigajoules.
-An attraction so....
-Go, go, go.
What are you doing, Flint Lockwood?
Just holding my hands
behind my back respectfully, sir.
-You know what you are, Lockwood?
-No.
A shenaniganizer.
A tomfool.
-You see my beautiful angel son, Cal?
-What's up?
I love him so much.
This is my only son.
I want him to have a bright future.
A future in which you don't ruin
our town's day...
...with one of your
crazy science thingies.
-Well, that's all behind me--
-You see this contact lens, Lockwood?
-This contact lens represent you.
-All right.
-And my eye represents my eye.
-Okay.
I got my eye on you.
-Oh, my gosh, a jaywalker.
-Hey.
And I've arranged for live coverage
from a major network...
...and their most experienced
professional reporter.
Oh, just send the intern.
She's cute and she's super perky.
Well, those are the only things we look
for in a TV weatherperson. Intern.
How would you like to do a weather
report from a rinky-dink island...
...in the middle of the ocean
as a favor to my cousin?
Really?
Can you believe it, Manny?
Temporary
professional meteorologist.
Okay, Manny, what about this?
Welcome, America,
I'm Sam Sparks.
Hello, America, Sam Sparks here.
America, hi. I didn't see you there.
It's me, Sam Sparks.
On my way across the ocean.
Now, when she gets here,
I wanna see a lot of smiling faces.
Act like, "Hey, whoa."
This is a great idea.
Weather News Network.
Weather news happens...
...or not.
Now we're over to Swallow Falls...
...where our intern
is on her first day on the job.
Or should I say, first gray on the job.
Looks pretty cloudy there, intern.
Hello, Sam Sparks, I'm America.
It's Swallow Falls degrees and--
Well, let's just go to the mayor.
Thank you and welcome,
national television audience.
You are about to witness
an historic event, undoubtedly....
And now, here to cut
the ceremonial ribbon...
...Swallow Falls' favorite son,
Baby Brent!
He's still got it, folks.
Yeah.
I'm the best person
in the whole town.
Food synthesis, go.
My chest hairs are tingling.
Something's wrong.
Well, here it is. The attraction
the whole world has been waiting for:
Sardine Land.
With rides and exhibits.
And featuring Shamo,
the world's largest sardine...
...and his flaming hoop of glory.
Those of you in the splash zone,
look out.
Yeah.
Cheeseburger.
Flint Lockwood.
Just a second.
I'm in the middle of a--
Well, looks like things in Swallow Falls
are sardine to get better. For--
What just happened to me?
Sorry.
No.
You're under arrest, Flint Lockwood.
Thank goodness you only caused
minimal damage to Sardine Land.
Come on.
I really shouldn't be running
with these.
Jump, jump, jump, run, run,
jump, jump, run.
-It's a good thing no one got hurt!
-Flint Lockwood!
I didn't get hurt, but that does
not mean that I'm not still mad at you.
Oh, my gosh. I am so sorry.
Are you okay?
-I didn't get a chance to--
-It's okay, it's just pain.
Sorry, I'm not myself today.
My whole career was ruined by some
crazy jerk riding a homemade rocket.
Wait a minute.
What is going on with your feet?
Spray-On Shoes.
They don't come off.
Cool.
This could solve
the untied shoes epidemic.
What are they made of, some kind of
elastic biopolymer adhesive?
Yeah.
Exactly.
I mean....
Wow, they're shiny. I'm Sam.
-Flint.
-Steve.
-Is that a Monkey Thought Translator?
Incredible.
Did you make all of this stuff?
-You hit me with a rocket.
-You kicked me in the face.
I said I was sorry.
Do you know how hard it is
to break into the weather game?
I spent my entire life building up
to that moment.
You get one shot at the show.
And if you don't make it...
...it's back to cleaning
the barometers.
Cheese?
But that could only mean....
Excited. Excited.
My machine works.
It really works!
Your machine?
Is that what that rocket was?
Do you like it?
I love it!
This is just amazing.
Look at this.
This is the greatest weather
phenomenon in history.
Hey, aren't you a weathergirl?
Manny, get your camera.
This just in: Our humiliated weather
intern is apparently back for more.
Thanks, Patrick. Okay, everybody,
you are not gonna believe this one...
...but I am standing
in the middle of a burger rain.
You may have seen
a meteor shower...
...but you've never seen a shower
meatier than this.
For a town stuck eating sardines,
this is totally manna from heaven.
This tastes significantly better
than sardines.
This is going to be big.
This food weather
was created intentionally...
...by meek-ish backyard tinkerer
Flint Lockwood.
Flint Lockwood?
Hi.
You're under arrest
for ruining Sardine Land.
Flint, those burgers were awesome.
The producer called and he was like,
"Everybody loves that food weather."
-Food weather.
-What?
This could be bigger
than Sardine Land.
-Can you make it rain food again?
-No.
-I don't know if I--
-You're gonna do it again?
You gotta be kidding.
Please, please, please.
-Yes.
-No.
-Give me one more chance.
-We know this was an accident.
-I know.
-Cheeseburgers from the sky...
...that's not natural.
My invention could save
the whole town.
You will be so proud of me, Dad.
Plus...
...there's a girl here.
Can you look me in the eye and
tell me you've got this under control...
...and it's not gonna end up
in a disaster?
Yes.
I've got this under control
and it's not gonna end in disaster.
-All right.
-Thanks, Dad.
-Oh, sure.
-Okay. So, Sam...
...this is where the magic happens.
Lick. Lick. Lick.
Welcome, Flint.
You seriously spend
a lot of time alone.
What?
So here's how it works.
Water goes in the top,
and food comes out the bottom.
When you shot it
into the stratosphere...
...you figured it would induce a phase
change from the cumulonimbus layer?
That's actually
a really smart observation.
I mean....
The clouds probably have water
in them...
...which, I guess, is why
you shot it up there in the first place.
Right, right. That's why I did that.
-On purpose.
-Right. Yeah.
-Right.
-Of course.
Okay.
The machine uses a principle
of hydro-genetic mutation.
Water molecules are bombarded
with microwave radiation...
...which mutates their genetic recipe
into any kind of food you want.
So....
-Pizza?
-Yes.
-Mashed potatoes?
-Peas?
-Yes, that's also a food.
-Steak? Apples?
-Yes.
-Apple sauce? BLT?
-I said any kind of food.
-Chicken wings?
Think about what you're saying
and if it's a food, yes.
-Baloney.
-Baloney. That is a food.
-How about Jell-O?
-Do you like Jell-O?
I love Jell-O.
I love Jell-O too.
Oh, and peanut butter, right?
Oh, no, no, no,
I am severely allergic to peanuts.
Hey, me too.
-What's it called?
-Peanut allergy.
-No, the machine.
-Of course.
It's called the Flint Lockwood
Diatonic Super-Mutating...
...Dynamic Food Replicator.
Or, for short:
The FLDSMDFR.
Fliminadifiser?
FLDSMDFR.
Fliminubahdibferer?
Fli.
Suh.
Fdiferf.
Manny, make sure you get this.
He's gonna make the food now.
Now?
Well, the thing is, I can't...
...wait to show you
this hilarious Internet video.
What?
Fight the power!
What is this?
It's so cute.
Pushing. Folding. Connecting.
Taping. Turning.
Painting. Switching.
Staring.
Motivating.
-Placing button.
-I can't believe I've been watching this...
-...for three hours.
-I know.
It's working.
What do you guys want for breakfast?
-Gummi Bears.
-Whoa, Steve, no.
We both know how you get
around Gummi Bears.
How about...
-...eggs.
-And toast.
Orange juice.
-And bacon.
-Bacon.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
To the computer.
So you're sure this is safe?
Don't worry. I have a Dangeometer
that lets us know...
...if the food is going
to over-mutate.
What happens
if the food over-mutates?
I don't know.
But that'll never happen.
All right, this probably
won't explode.
What?
Bacon.
Those cheeseburgers
were only the beginning...
...because a breakfast system
is on its way to Swallow Falls.
My forecast?
Sunny side up.
-Yeah.
Flint, my boy. Can you do lunch?
All right, here's the skinny:
You keep making it rain
the snackadoos...
...weathergirl provides
free advertising...
...I have taken out
a very high-interest loan...
...to convert this Podunk town
into a tourist food-topia.
All you have to do is make it rain food
three meals a day...
...every day
for the foreseeable future...
...and in 30 days we hold a grand
reopening of the island...
...as a must-see cruise destination.
And everyone, everywhere...
...is going to love your invention.
Do you think so?
I know so.
Now that's what I call
poultry in motion.
Mr. Lockwood,
may I please have waffles?
-Falafels?
-Jellybeans.
-Avocado.
-Coming right up.
Leftovers?
Not a problem with Flint Lockwood's
latest invention, the Outtasighter...
...so-named because it catapults
uneaten food out of sight...
...and therefore, out of mind.
Jellybeans!
Awesome.
-BLT.
-Doughnuts.
Pie.
Gummi bears.
-Fish.
-Crème brûlée!
A pizza stuffed inside a turkey...
...the whole thing deep-fried
and dipped in chocolate.
It's me, the mayor.
You look different.
Did you get a new haircut?
Yes, I did. Thank you for noticing.
-I love you.
-Thanks, Dad. I love you.
I love spending time with you, Dad.
Hey, Dad, I'm headed back
to the lab.
If you wanna come,
I could show you how I make the food.
No, thanks.
That techno-food, it's too complicated
for an old fisherman.
Got it.
Could still use your help around here,
though, you know.
I'm working
with the mayor now, Dad.
I mean, the town's grand reopening
is in, like, a week.
Right. Got it.
Flint Lockwood?
Yeah?
It's my son Cal's birthday tomorrow...
...and I was just wondering if you
could make it rain something special.
Well, I'm pretty backed up
on requests.
Plus, you're always mean to me.
It'll be just one time...
...for my special angel's special day.
I don't know.
You know, I don't wanna
overwork the machine, so....
Okay. I knew it was a long shot.
I just wanted Cal to see how much
his father loves him.
I thought you would understand.
You know how fathers always trying
to express...
...their love and appreciation
for their sons.
Earl, wait.
Touch. Touch. Touch.
I've got an idea.
Happy birthday, son.
Dad?
This is your day. Go have fun.
-I love you guys. You're awesome.
-I love you too, son.
-Have a good time, baby.
-Ice cream!
Yeah! Cool.
Strawberry's my favorite.
Come on, Dad.
I don't know, Cal.
This doesn't look safe!
I love you, son.
I know, Dad. You tell me every day.
Flint, this is amazing.
And designing the ice cream
to accumulate into scoops...
...I don't know how
you're gonna top this.
Maybe with hot fudge.
Hey, Flint.
You wanna be in a snowball fight
with us?
Flint, what's the problem?
I've never actually been
in a snowball fight.
-Really?
-I don't even know the rules.
Is there like a point system or is it...
-...to the death?
-No--
You've nev--? I mean, look, even
Steve is throwing chocolate snowballs.
So like this?
No, harder than that.
Snowball.
Snowball, snowball, snowball.
Snowball. Snowball.
Well, something to be said
for enthusiasm.
Snowball!
Snowball and snowball.
Kids? What's going on?
Snowball.
-Snowball.
-Snowball. Snowball.
I scream, you scream...
...we all scream for Flint Lockwood's
latest tasty town-wide treat...
...with flurries of frozen fun
on what the mayor declared to be...
...an ice cream snow day.
He'd also like to invite everyone
in the world to catch a cruise liner...
...and come on down
this Saturday...
...for the grand opening
of Chew And Swallow...
...a town that is truly à la mode.
A town that is truly
topped with ice cream.
With today's scoop
for the Weather News Network...
...I'm Sam Sparks.
Flint, this is the best breakfast ever.
That's it!
Researching. Role-playing.
Dialing.
Waiting.
-Sam Sparks.
-Hanging up.
Regretting. Re-psyching.
Saying what I'm doing.
-Flint?
-"Hi, Sam, how are you? That's nice.
I was wondering if you would like
to go on a da--"
Activity with me tomorrow.
-Okay.
-Great, bye. Meet me in the forest.
Nailed it. Gotta go, Steve.
Keep an eye on the lab for me.
Steve.
Foster still at the plate.
And nobody out.
Where are we going?
Oh, nowhere.
I just thought it'd be nice...
...for the two of us
to go on a walk together.
Like you do as friends.
Oh, my, what's that?
Jell-O's my favorite.
You never made a request, so...
...I made one for you.
Flint?
Join me.
But how did you--?
I made it rain Jell-O, then I gathered
it up with the Outtasighter...
...and then I brought it here
and pressed it...
...into a gigantic custom-carved plastic
Tupperware mold I made. No big deal.
Everything's made of Jell-O.
This piano, those sconces...
...that ghetto blaster, that Jell-O,
that aquarium...
...that Venus de Milo
with your face on it...
...next to a Michelangelo's David
that also has your face.
Come on, Sam,
what are you waiting for?
Nothing!
Yeah.
Cannonball.
Belly flop.
Why did I do that?
-So Jell-O.
-Right. Right, right.
It's a solid, it's a liquid...
...it's a visco-elastic polymer made of
polypeptide chains, but you eat it.
I mean...
...it tastes good.
-Why do you do that?
-Do what?
Say something super smart
and then bail from it.
Can you keep a secret?
No.
But this time, sure, yeah.
Okay. Well, it was a really
long time ago, but I, too, was...
...a nerd.
Too?
When I was a little girl...
...I wore a ponytail, I had glasses...
...and I was totally obsessed
with the science of weather.
Other girls wanted a Barbie.
I wanted a Doppler Weather
Radar 2000 Turbo.
But all the kids used to taunt me
with this lame song.
It wasn't even clever.
Four-eyes, four-eyes
You need glasses to see
Go on.
So I got a new look...
...gave up the science-y
smart stuff...
...and I was never
made fun of again.
And I still need these glasses,
but I never wear them.
-I'll bet you look great with glasses on.
-I'm not--
And on they go.
-What?
-Nothing.
Wait.
It's a Jell-O scrunchie.
And now, the reveal.
I mean, you were okay before...
...but now...
...you're beautiful.
No, I'm not. I can't go out in public
like this.
Well, why not?
I mean, this is the real you, right?
Smart.
Bespectacled.
Who wouldn't wanna see that?
You know, I've never met anyone
like you, Flint Lockwood.
Me either.
But about you.
Flint, you have a call
Is your phone ringing?
That's weird.
Someone must've changed my ring.
Oh, it's the mayor.
Do you mind if I take this?
No, no, no.
-Go ahead, take it. That's fine.
-I'm sorry. It's important.
-I should be going too. It's getting late.
-I'm just gonna step outside.
Dad, you came.
I have so much to tell you.
-Do I look all right?
-You look great. Come on, let's go.
Dad, I almost kissed a girl.
-It's Baby Brent, you know?
-It was the coolest thing-- Hi.
-I should be on the list.
-Hey, Brian.
What? You're letting that guy in?
That guy's a nerd.
Hey, how's it going?
Oh, thank you. Thank you so much.
Thank you.
A toast.
To Flint and his delicious steaks.
-Oh, thanks. Thank you.
-Very nice place.
Oh, wow, thank you.
-Flint Lockwood.
-Earl.
So no roof.
Yep. You just hold out your plate.
And I even made it rain
your favorite:
Meat.
Okay.
So you know how the grand reopening
of the town is tomorrow?
Well, the mayor has asked me
to cut the ribbon.
He said my invention
saved the town.
Aren't you proud of me?
Well...
...doesn't this steak look
a little big to you?
Yeah, it's a big steak. I mean, every
steak is not exactly the same size.
Did you even hear what I just said?
Son, look around.
I'm not sure this is good for people.
Maybe you should think about
turning this thing off.
It's making everybody happy.
Everybody except you.
When are you gonna accept
that this is who I am...
...instead of trying to get me to work
in some boring tackle shop?
Well...
...you seem like you know
what you're doing, then.
I guess I'll just get out of your way.
Get with the times, man.
I mean, there's no pleasing
that guy.
He just wants to take anything
good I do and just smoosh it.
These are big hot dogs.
Man.
I mean, this isn't that bad.
-Is it, Steve?
-Yellow.
You're right, Steve.
The Dangeometer is in the yellow.
I don't know what to do.
I do.
Declare these hot dogs
to be delicious!
Oh, no.
How did you get in here?
Tomorrow's the big day, Flint.
The entire town's fate is resting
on your food weather.
I'm thinking pasta.
Some light apps.
I know you won't let us down.
Well, Mr. Mayor, I think there's
something you should see.
What?
This is the molecular structure
of a hot dog that fell last week.
And this is the molecular structure
of a hot dog that fell today.
The machine uses
microwave radiation...
...to mutate the genetic recipe
of the food.
The more we ask it to make,
the more clouds it takes in...
...the more radiation it emits, the more
these molecules could over-mutate.
I think that's why the food
is getting bigger.
Here's what I heard:
"Science, science, science, bigger."
And bigger is better.
Everyone's gonna love
these new portion sizes.
I know I do.
My dad thinks I should turn it off.
Geniuses like us are never understood
by their fathers, Flint.
But what if things go--?
Who needs the approval
of one family member...
...when you can have it
from millions of acquaintances?
Not to mention that little cutlet,
Sam Sparks.
And me.
I've always felt that you were
like a son to me, Flint.
And I'm gonna be so proud of you
tomorrow when you cut that ribbon...
...save the town...
...and prove to everybody
what a great inventor you are.
So here's the cheese:
You can keep it going...
...get everything you've ever wanted...
...and be the great man
I know you can be.
Or you can turn it off...
...ruin everything...
...and no one will ever like you.
It's your choice.
Choice.
Okay.
I mean, bigger is better...
...right?
Oh, yeah.
Spaghetti. Asparagus. Celery.
Garlic bread. Meatball. Shrimp.
-Looks safe to me.
-And sanitary too.
Who's hungry?
Welcome, tourists,
to Chew And Swallow.
That is one big mayor.
Delight in our nacho-cheese
hot springs.
Allow your kids to eat
all the junk food they want...
...in our completely
unsupervised Kid Zone!
I've got jellybeans for teeth.
And when the fun is done...
...gaze upon the sunset
cresting over Mount Leftovers.
From which we're protected
by a presumably indestructible dam.
We've got people here today
from all around the world...
...from as far as China
to West Virginia.
Also I think there's
some Canadians here.
-You need to look at this.
-Why aren't you on TV?
You're supposed
to be broadcasting this.
There's a problem.
The food's getting bigger.
I know, it's great. Bigger portion sizes.
Everyone loves it.
I'm not sure we're doing
the right thing here.
What if we've bitten off more
than we can chew?
For the first time in my life, everybody
loves something that I've done.
Why can't you just be happy for me...
...and go say the weather
or something. Jeez.
And without further ado...
...our town's hero
and my metaphorical son...
...Flint Lockwood.
Yeah, Flint.
Thank you. Thank you, everyone.
-Sign my shrimp.
-Thank you.
-Yeah. Yeah.
-I love you.
I admire your quirkiness, dude.
Brent, we're gonna need you
to hand over the ceremonial scissors.
But--
No.
-You can't. You can't take them. No.
-Here you go.
I'm Baby Brent.
Put your clothes back on.
Who am I?
Go ahead, Flint.
Everybody loves you.
Lockwood! Lockwood! Lockwood!
Danger. Danger. Danger.
Salt-and-pepper wind?
Oregano.
Sam, wait. No, I can turn it off.
I can turn it off.
All right, kid, it's all gonna be okay.
Oh, no.
-Pardon me.
-Excuse me.
-No problem.
No.
-Gummi Bears.
-Not now, Steve.
Condiments? Salt? Pepper?
Flint.
This is Sam Sparks,
live from Chew And Swallow...
...where a spaghetti twister--
Sam, hey, we love a good storm
over here, but you look like a nerd.
Patrick, several children are stranded
in the path of this tomato tornado.
My tummy hurts.
Cal.
What is that, a scrunchie? I haven't
seen one of those since 1995.
What? We have
an actual weather emergency.
Well, we'll get right back
to that storm...
...and hopefully Sam'll look
a little more appealing.
Steve, we just have to upload the kill
code and then we'll shut down the--
What are you doing here?
I've been ordering dinner
for the last 10 minutes.
-Is something going on?
-I've gotta stop the machine.
Everyone's in danger
because of me.
Oh, it can't be that bad.
-No.
-Well, I'm out of here.
I can still stop the order
with the kill code.
-Sending kill code.
-I'm back.
Got to get the button.
Play. Fun. Fun. Play.
Hey, Flint. It's been nice
to beet you.
That's a radish.
That was the only way
to communicate with the machine.
What exactly did you order?
A Vegas-style all-you-can-eat buffet.
Jellybean. Watermelon.
Marshmallow. Pretzel. Sushi.
Cheeseburger. Pretzel. Egg salad.
Strawberry. Marshmallow.
Strawberry.
-Is everyone okay?
-Yeah.
Help, somebody.
Help me, please.
It's my son.
We need a doctor.
Is anyone here a doctor? Anyone?
I am a doctor.
You are?
I was, back in Guatemala.
I came here for a better life.
Pretty great decision, eh?
How is he, doc?
He's in a food coma.
Too much junk food.
I need a celery, stat.
Here you go.
-Daddy?
-Oh, Cal. Cal.
I love you, son.
Looks like everything
turned out okay.
Not yet, it hasn't.
That twister was an amuse-bouche
compared to what's on the way.
-What's an amuse-bouche?
-Manny, patch us through.
Go.
Cute report, Nancy.
Hey. Hey. Four-eyes.
Can it, Patrick.
We are about to be in the epicenter
of a perfect food storm.
It's going to spread
across the globe.
I've calculated the Coriolis
acceleration of the storm system.
First, it'll hit New York...
...then Paris...
...then the Jiayuguan Pass
in eastern China.
And in four hours the entire northern
hemisphere will be one big potluck.
Flint?
Hey, Dad.
What are you doing?
Well, I tried to help everybody...
...but instead I ruined everything.
I'm just a piece of junk.
So I threw myself away.
Along with all these
dumb inventions.
This is junk.
Oh, son. Listen, when your boat is,
when it's listing...
...and if it's not running,
you know--
Don't worry, Dad, I get it.
Mom was wrong about me.
I'm not an inventor.
I should've just quit when you said.
Well...
...when it rains, you put on a coat.
Dad, you know I don't understand
fishing metapho--
What?
My coat.
Come on, Steve.
We've got diem to carpe.
Kill code downloading.
Redesigning. Virtualizing.
Cutting.
Welding. Forging.
-Wiring.
-Helping.
Testing.
Yes.
Flying Car 2.
Now with wings.
Hey, I had a weird dream
like this once.
I have a macaroni
on my head.
Run.
No school!
Still nothing-nothing in the bottom of
the third inning.
Everyone.
I want to apologize.
Especially to you, Sam.
But I have a plan.
This flash drive contains a kill code.
I will fly up into that food storm,
plug it into the machine...
...and shut it down forever...
...while you guys evacuate
the island, using brea--
This is all his fault. Get him.
There he is! Get him!
Get Flint.
Let's rock his car back and forth.
Hey!
This mess we're in
is all our faults.
Me, I didn't even protect
my own son.
Look, I'm as mad at Flint as you are.
In fact, when he gets out of that car,
I'm gonna slap him in the face.
I know Flint Lockwood made the food,
but it was made-to-order.
And now it's time for all of us
to pay the bill.
Thank you, Earl.
-Sorry.
-It's okay.
-Let's go build some boats.
-Yeah.
I'm gonna go build a boat.
I'm coming with you.
You're gonna need someone
to navigate you through that storm.
I can't let you do this alone.
-Oh, Sam, I'm so sorry.
-Are you kidding?
-Well, I just thought that we--
-No.
Okay.
-You are going to need a copilot.
-You're a pilot too?
Yes. I am also a particle physicist.
-Really?
-No, that was a joke.
I am also a comedian.
-Let's do this thing.
-I'm coming too.
Brent, that's okay.
No, it's not okay.
I've been coasting on my fame
since I was a baby.
But it was all just an illusion.
Maybe up there
I'll find out who I really am.
The car's pretty full, so....
Yeah.
Brent.
Okay.
Good luck, son.
Steve.
Pea-soup fog.
Manny, hit the wipers.
There's massive gastro-precipitation
accumulated around the machine.
It's almost as if it's....
Inside a giant meatball.
Water goes in the top...
...a food hurricane
comes out the bottom.
Glad I'm wearing a diaper.
Anybody order pizza?
Hold on.
The pizza's chasing us?
Sentient food? That's impossible.
Unless its molecular structure's
mutated into super food!
That's been genetically engineered
to protect the FLDSMDFR.
Pizza.
Pizza. Pizza. Pizza.
That was close. I mean, can you
imagine if we lost this kill code?
-Tim's Tackle Shop.
-Dad.
You're okay, great.
I need a favor. The fate of the world
depends on it!
Okay, then, skipper.
What do you need?
Go into my lab, get on my computer
and e-mail a file to my cell phone.
All right.
-Want me to drive?
-Yeah, okay.
You're a lot better than me.
Okay, here's the plan:
Sam and I will enter the meateroid
through the intake here...
...which should lead us straight
to the FLDSMDFR.
Manny, you and Steve stay
on the plane. Don't spray that.
Once my dad e-mails me the kill code,
we'll destroy the machine...
...and rendezvous
at the western blowhole in--
-How long until the world's destroyed?
-Twenty minutes.
Just before then.
What about me, Brent?
What do I do?
You can be president
of the back seat.
Deploy hatch.
Car upside down, go.
Ladies first?
No?
All right.
Wait for me.
Great. Okay, I'm good.
As long as we stay on course,
it should be a straight shot to the--
Yeah!
We're a team.
We've landed here
in some kind of exhaust vent.
If we go this way, the Flamidabager
should be right down this air shaft.
Brent, get out of that pie.
What's that?
Oh, boy.
Welcome, Flint.
That's fry oil.
Flint, you have a call.
Flint, you have a--
Dad. Oh, okay, great.
On the screen there's a file
marked "kill code."
-Wha--?
-Move that into my e-mail window...
...type in my name,
and press "send."
-Window?
-Okay, Dad...
...you see the thing that looks like
a little piece of paper?
Use the mouse to drag it.
-Drag it? Drag it.
-Drag it. Drag it.
Right? Okay. Great. Okay, great.
It's not dragging.
Drag it across the desktop.
-That didn't do anything.
-Of course it didn't! You know what?
Go, go, go.
Hoist those sails. Toast that bread.
We are running out of time.
Let's move out. Go, go, go.
We can do it.
Come on, move it, move it.
Good job. That's what I'm talking
about. Everybody head to the docks.
Wait, wait.
I have an important announcement.
See you, suckers.
Bon voyage.
And bon appétit.
-Cal.
-Calvin.
Cal, get back here.
-Foodalanche.
-Cal.
I'm not gonna lose you again.
Baby.
Hold on tight, Calvin.
Everybody head south.
We gotta stay ahead of that storm.
-Now what?
-Just click "send."
Flint, the Fliminadifiserser's
right down there!
-Dad, hurry.
-Send. Send.
Oh, wait.
Dad? Dad? Can you hear me?
Dad?
Hey, guys?
Holy crap balls.
Go, go, go.
I don't know.
I think they're kind of cute.
I mean, this one just walked
right up to me and--
He's got me!
-They ate Brent.
Dad, I'm surrounded
by man-eating chickens right now.
So if this is goodbye...
...thanks for trying
to set me straight.
Figured it out a little late, I guess.
Okay, bye.
Dad.
Hey, give me that phone back.
Baby Brent?
I'm not Baby Brent anymore.
I'm Chicken Brent.
And I'm finally contributing
to society.
Crotch kick.
Now go, you crazy kids,
and save the world.
You did it, Chicken Brent.
You really did it.
Go, go, go.
It should be right down this hole.
That's peanut brittle.
If either one of us touches it,
we'll go into anaphylactic shock.
Actually, I'm not entirely allergic
to peanuts.
I might have just said that
to get you to like me.
So you really thought having allergies
would make you more attractive?
Mustache.
Mus--
-Sesame bagel.
-Hey, taxi.
-Taxi.
I asked for extra mustard.
I was right.
Hot tea?
Did he say hot tea?
"You are about to be crushed
by a giant corn."
Run.
It looks like the food storm
is following an unusual pattern...
...of hitting the world's
famous landmarks first...
...and is now spreading
to the rest of the globe.
What the what?
Hurry up, guys.
After I plug my phone into
the FLDSMDFR and destroy it...
...I'll tug on the licorice twice
and you'll pull me back up, okay?
Sounds great.
Oh, no.
You got cut, didn't you?
It's just a scratch.
Brent, you need to take Sam back to
the plane to get her an allergy shot.
Just a second.
What? No.
-Let go, Sam.
-I'm not gonna let you go.
Flint, you'll be stuck down there.
It's not ideal, no.
Come with us. We'll start over.
We'll live underground.
Use bacon for clothes.
Sam, that's not a very good plan.
It is if it means
I don't have to lose you.
Look, I like you, okay?
Like-- Like, as a friend?
No.
Like, "like you" like you.
Me too.
But about you.
Goodbye, Sam.
Flint. No.
Hang on, Sam.
Dr. Manny's got the medicine
for your face.
Pickles.
Beets.
Banana.
Strawberry.
-Manny, we're on our way. Hurry.
-Hang on, Sam.
I'm circling the blowhole.
Scared.
Gummi Bears.
Play with us, play with us.
Eat us, eat us.
Hungry.
Hungry. Gummi Bears. Gummi Bears.
Gummi Bears. Steve hungry. Hungry.
Steve starving. Hungry.
Hungry. Starving.
Manny. Where are you?
-She touched a peanut or something.
-Oh, boy.
Corn.
Grabbing.
Tying. Throwing.
Waiting.
Swinging.
Sorry, old friend.
The kitchen's closed.
Fight the power!
Dad.
No.
When it rains, you put on a coat...
...of Spray-On Shoes.
Yeah.
Just-- There were chickens--
Where's Flint?
No!
I know, kid.
I know.
-Cool.
-Yeah. All right.
Flint?
I'm sorry.
Your son was a great man.
-Steve.
-Flint.
-Brent.
-Cal.
-Steve.
-Flint.
-Earl.
-You, guy.
-Steve.
Sam.
Flint.
-Flint.
-Dad.
-Steve.
Flint.
Look, when you--
When you cast your line...
...if it's not straight--
Oh, for crying out loud.
I'm proud of you, Flint.
I'm amazed that someone
as ordinary as me...
...could be the father of someone
as extraordinary as you.
You're talented,
you're a total original.
And your lab is breathtaking.
Your mom, she always knew
you were going to be special.
And if she were alive today,
she'd tell us both:
"I told you so."
Now, look,
when I take this thing off...
...and you hear me
make a fishing metaphor...
...just know
that fishing metaphor means:
I love my son.
I love you too, Dad.
So where were we?
You were about to kiss me.
Were you gonna kiss me back?
Why don't you find out?
Because I don't want to go for it
and then get shut down again.
-Just kiss me.
-You know--
Yeah. I'm a chicken.
This was not well thought out.